<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hung-Chung Kuo</title>
    <description>A Passionate Programmer
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:44:48 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:44:48 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blockchain - Introduction</title>
        <description>&lt;header class=&quot;blogFirstParagraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/blockchain.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;width:120px; height:120px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blockchain, knows as the distributed ledger, is a decentralized database that can store transactions records in each node participate in the network. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Why it is called 'blockchain' ?&lt;/h5&gt;Because it is a chain of many blocks. Each block store some transaction records, and all the transaction records form blockchain. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;How does it works ?&lt;/h5&gt;
Just imagine it is a ledger. If you want to join this network, you have to download and synchronize this ledger to your local computer. This results in everyone owns a ledger in their own node. &lt;br /&gt;
If any new transaction record comes in, all the nodes will be notified. If all nodes accept this as an valid transaction, it means that all participants have reach consensus and agree upon the establishment of this transaction. Lastly, this new record will insert into all the ledger everyone holds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;The purpose of blockchain in the beginning &lt;/h5&gt;

The concept of blockchain is proposed by Satoshi Nakamoto in 2009, and he introduced two concepts simultaneously in that year.&lt;br /&gt;The first concept is the Bitcoin, a decentralized peer to peer online currency that maintains value without the existence of banking. However, there is another concept which is equally important as Bitcoin, and it is the concept of proof of work-based blockchain to allow for public agreements on the order of transactions (Buterin, 2004). &lt;br /&gt;Blockchain is able to identify the sequence of each transaction and provide consensus mechanism, making the implementation of Bitcoin complete. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;What does blockchain actually solves? ?&lt;/h5&gt;
There are four main characteristics of blockchain proposed by Fecher (2016), and they are listed as follows:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-top:1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Decentralized&lt;/h5&gt;
Blockchain decentralizes the way we store data and manage information, potentially leading to a reduced role for one of the most important regulatory actors in our society: the middleman. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-top:1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Distributed &lt;/h5&gt;
The distributed characteristic means that there is no single hardware infrastructure storing and running the service. Often, this means that a copy of a database exists on several computers inside the network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-top:1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Immutability &lt;/h5&gt;
It means that strictly speaking data cannot be changed in blockchain. However, in practice, this means that data cannot be changed without leaving a trace, which indicates that each transaction is recorded. And this means that old versions can be recovered and that any changes will be protocolled in a system. It is like comparing an excel sheet in which values can be changed at will to a piece of paper. On paper a trace of every manipulation is left displayed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-top:1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Transparent &lt;/h5&gt;
Transparent means that a computer program is actually running as is publicized. Meanwhile, we must rely upon others to calculate things (e.g. impact factor) or to apply post processing tools to research data as they claim that they are doing it; after blockchain revolution, this will be transparent and provable to peer nodes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Which scenario does blockchain fit in the best ?&lt;/h5&gt;
Nowadays, many organizations hold the ambition to provide an ecosystem that can be fully trusted by stakeholders, including customers, supplier, or other corporate partners. However, the issues of transparency, unavailability, and untraceable can be hard to deal with, and the blockchain technology can solve these problems once and for all. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But blockchain does not fit in every industry. Based on the four characteristic mentioned above, we have to consider whether they are crucial to the provided service or not. If 'Trust&quot; is an important advantage to your service (e.g. third party payment), you can consider integrate your service with blockchain. However, you may think that the current architecture used by many services already did a great job, and you might start wondering the necessity of blockchain integration. ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blockchain/technology/2017/11/12/blockchain-introduction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blockchain/technology/2017/11/12/blockchain-introduction.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blockchain</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blockchain - Prologue</title>
        <description>&lt;header class=&quot;blogFirstParagraph&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/me.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;width:120px; height:120px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first post and I've decided to take blockchain as the very first topic in my blog. &lt;br /&gt;I'll continue updating the following posts irregularly, and the topic will not be restricted to blockchain but all kinds of new technology I am interested.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;header&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Prologue&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some thoughts about blockchain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, Bitcoin &amp;amp; Ethereum has been dicussed a lot. As the foundation of these two applications, many people start to imagine the potential and possibility blockchain might bring to our world.

Well.. blockchain indeed holds the potential to improve the service and process in many industries, but it is not a universal solution to all kinds of scenarios. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My master thesis is about how to help the entrepreneur to design a sustainable blockchain-based ecosystem. In order to testify the methodolgy I've proposed, I've built a DApp (Decentralized Application) based on the guildeline from my research, hoping the result of the DApp turns out to be positive so that my propositions can be testified. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the process of the research and implementation, I've encounter many issues due to my misunderstanding of the core concept and meaning of the blockchain, which leads to a waste of this amzing technology. To fully utilize the benefits of blockchain, we must understand the purpose and characteristics of it, or we might merely treat this new technology as another kinds of computing infrastructure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;header&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Blockchain series posts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following list shows the contents of my blockchain series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Introduction&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Key Concepts&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Platforms Nowadays&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Applications&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'll start from some basic introductions and examples of blockchain, but I'll go though it very quickly and spend more time on discussing some advance issues of blockchain. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; I'll share all I know and some traps we might fall into easily when desinging &amp;amp; implementing a DApp. If you have any suggestions or comments, feel free to open a issue and I'll answer it ASAP : ) &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blockchain/technology/2017/11/09/blockchain-introduction-prologue.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blockchain/technology/2017/11/09/blockchain-introduction-prologue.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blockchain</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
